<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>CanesCast</title>
		<description>The Eye of the Lethbridge Hurricanes</description>
		<link>http://canescast.ca</link>
		<atom:link href="http://canescast.ca/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Farewell From CanesCast</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After six years, roughly 360 games broadcast, more than 20,000 updates posted to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/canescast&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and nearly 4,500 photos shared on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/canescast&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, the CanesCast team has decided to hang up our skates. It’s been a great journey, and we thank you for being part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has truly been an enjoyable experience for us, one that I would choose to be a part of all over again. Life has a way of pulling in different directions, though, and the time has come for the members of our team to move on to new pursuits. It will be a strange feeling not to be wearing the CanesCast jacket when the puck drops next September, but for various reasons, the time has come to retire CanesCast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the Hurricanes have your game updates covered on Twitter now, so make sure you’re following them: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www/twitter.com/whlhurricanes&quot;&gt;@WHLHurricanes&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re looking for a fan perspective and a bit of commentary, give those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/Hecklers_Row&quot;&gt;@Hecklers_Row&lt;/a&gt; rowdies behind the visitors’ bench a follow, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sign off for the final time here at CanesCast.ca, I would like to express my gratitude to the many people who made it all possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, thanks to Ryan Shannon who got the ball rolling on all of this. You think big, and I hope we came close to scratching the surface of what you&amp;#39;d envisioned CanesCast could become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, thanks to the to Lethbridge Hurricanes for granting us access, and treating us as members of the media, even if we had no prior experience or knowledge when it came to being sports media. In particular I’d like to thank, Ryan Ohashi and Jim Bradley who believed in our idea and let us explore our vision, and then to Esther Madziya and Neil Fraser who continued to support us when they joined the team. It has been a pleasure to work alongside all of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several sponsors have provided support to help us cover our operating costs over the years as well, so thank you to each of them: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lethbridgewebdesign.ca&quot;&gt;Lethbridge Web Design&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitlethbridge.com&quot;&gt;Visit Lethbridge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.viewlethbridge.com&quot;&gt;Jennifer Brodoway of ViewLethbridge.com&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mygreatrate.ca&quot;&gt;Shaun Serafini of Dominion Lending&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Morgan Martin and Mackenzie Hientz, members of the CanesCast crew who posted updates to Twitter, captured game photos, and wrote articles, thank you for your hard work in ensuring that CanesCast was always producing quality content. I know I can be a little controlling when I’ve got a vision in my head, and I thank you for being patient in working with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the Hurricane fans who have followed along and interacted with us over the years: thank you for giving us a reason to do what we do. We are fans just like you, and I’m happy to have been a part of bringing the Hurricane news and action to you online during our tenure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last, but certainly not least, to Mark Huxley, my fellow CanesCaster from the beginning, and the Don Cherry to my Ron MacLean: thank you for your contagious enthusiasm and dedication to the Hurricanes and CanesCast. I’m proud of the work that we have done, and the fun that we’ve had at the rink. So long, and thanks for all the fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3797/13260066703_f07547e9ff_n_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mark and Josh in the press box before the final CanesCast&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 22:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2014/03/farewell-from-canescast/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2014/03/farewell-from-canescast/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>CanesCast Radio - The Farewell Episode</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In fitting fashion, our final episode of the CanesCast Radio podcast is delayed a couple of weeks beyond when we had hoped to post it. Here you have it, though: In two segments, Mark, Mac, and I discuss the Hurricanes of 2013/14 as well as looking back on the past six years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/141804138&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/141804583&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for listening.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 09:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2014/03/canescast-radio-farewell-episode/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2014/03/canescast-radio-farewell-episode/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On ice with the Lethbridge Sledge Hockey Club</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Right now feels like a good time to highlight some of the good things happening for hockey in Lethbridge. Fortunately, I’ve got just the thing: Let’s check in with the Lethbridge Sledge Hockey Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t familiar with sledge hockey, it is an accessible form of hockey played sitting down on a sledge and using two short hockey sticks with picks on the butt ends allowing the players to push off and move around the ice. You may remember a demonstration held during an intermission at a Hurricanes game about two years ago (as seen in this story’s lead photo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve wanted to give sledge hockey a try for a while now, probably ever since seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FiDvpFeipEE&quot;&gt;Rick Mercer giving it a try with the Canadian national team&lt;/a&gt;. Last month I got the opportunity, so I mounted the GoPro on my helmet, strapped into a sledge and hit the ice with the club for an evening to learn the sport. Take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/4siYJxGOaYc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Makrina Morozowski for showing me the ropes and sharing a bit of information about the sport. She also gave me some pointers on how to manoeuvre the sledge around the ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iEUwl5Fu-FM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that moving around on the sledge wasn’t as difficult as I’d expected, although my blades were a lot farther apart than what you see in the photo above, making my sledge harder to tip over. Stick handling the puck back and forth from one stick to the other under my legs was novel for me. The most noticeably difficult part of the game, I found, was managing to control a puck while also having to use the sticks for steering and propelling the sledge. That skill, I suspect, takes plenty of practice to become proficient with, and I certainly plan on heading out again to get some more practice at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to give sledge hockey a try for yourself, get ahold of the club through &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lethsledge&quot;&gt;Twitter at @lethsledge&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Lethbridge-Sledge-Hockey-Club/529622590427365&quot;&gt;on their Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/11/on-ice-with-lethbridge-sledge-hockey-club/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/11/on-ice-with-lethbridge-sledge-hockey-club/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Give Pilon the Forsberg Treatment</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With three players leaving the team and demanding trades, the 2013/14 Lethbridge Hurricanes are beginning to look a lot like the Prince George Cougars of the past few seasons. This time around, I think Brad Robson ought to take a page from Cougars GM  Dallas Thompson’s playbook and draw a line in the sand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may recall last season that former first overall bantam pick &lt;a href=&quot;http://ca.sports.yahoo.com/blogs/jrhockey-buzzing-the-net/alex-forsberg-side-falling-cougars-024744631.html&quot;&gt;Alex Forsberg decided he’d had enough of playing for the perennial rebuilding franchise&lt;/a&gt;, and headed home to await the inevitable trade. Only, that trade never materialized. Thompson didn’t hear any offers that he liked, and the trade deadline came and went with Forsberg still a Cougar. Forsberg stayed in Saskatchewan playing Junior A for the remainder of the season and was not selected in this summer’s NHL entry draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a coaching change in Prince George and a summer to consider the situation, Forsberg returned to the Cougars for training camp this year and has so far tallied 14 points in 19 games. The Cougars are holding down eighth spot in the western conference and could return to the post season for the first time since they were swept out of the 2011 playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, before entering the WHL, Alex Forsberg played for the Beardy’s Blackhawks, the same club as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lethbridgehurricanes.com/article/canes-d-man-leaves-team&quot;&gt;the Hurricanes’ latest hold out, Ryan Pilon&lt;/a&gt;. I say it’s time that the organization treat Pilon’s request similar to how Prince George dealt with Forsberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision to acquiesce to Sam McKechnie and Jaimen Yakubowski and their trade requests could prove to be an ugly precedent, giving players unhappy with the mounting losses an easy escape. Coaches and management should not be immune to criticism or accountability, but at some point the players need to take some responsibility for the underperformance as well. Requesting a trade and going home implies that a player doesn’t feel he is bears any responsibility. It’s selfish, and it puts the team in a bad position where they can’t possibly get fair trade value for the player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest: The Hurricanes are far enough out of the hunt right now that this is a lost season. In order to finish the season at a modest .500 record, which &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be enough to sneak into a seventh or eighth playoff spot in the tough eastern conference, the Hurricanes would need to win more than 32 of their remaining 54 games. Now is the time to send a message to those players who “don’t want to be here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let Pilon stay home. Sure, Robson should listen to offers, but he should follow Thompson’s example and refuse to part with a talented player for less than he’s worth. Let him sit and sweat it out, and be prepared to let the trade deadline go by without making a move. Sure, it’s a risk, and the Hurricanes may never get a fair return for him. But granting three trade requests in less than a month is a risk, too, because it tells players that they don’t need to be accountable for the team’s performance and they can hit the eject button when things get too tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex Forsberg was quoted as saying, “...it was tough to not be on a team with a winning attitude. I just felt we could have been better than we were.” I’m sure Pilon feels the same way, but for a player wearing an A, ostensibly one of the leaders of the team, he needs to understand that establishing that winning attitude comes from inside the dressing room, and walking out on your teammates isn’t what winners do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 22:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/11/give-pilon-the-forsberg-treatment/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/11/give-pilon-the-forsberg-treatment/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Versteeg Wants to Own the Hurricanes</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;On the heels of a heartbreaking overtime defeat to the Moose Jaw Warriors last night, the Lethbridge Hurricanes ownership has taken the spotlight. During the off-season rumours surfaced about a group including former players having an interest in purchasing the team. The change of direction behind the bench seemed to quiet those rumours. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The summer’s rumours never included any names, but Kris Versteeg would invariably be mentioned in any speculation, given his connection to the team and city. Today we got confirmation of that by way of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lethbridgeherald.com/sports/hurricanes/2013/10/versteeg-writes-open-letter-to-fans-shareholders/&quot;&gt;an open letter published in the Lethbridge Herald&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='“I, and the people involved alongside me, have the best interests of the Lethbridge Hurricanes at heart and want to make the organization a successful WHL hockey club.”'&gt;
Versteeg emphasized that he did not intend to kick the Hurricanes while they are down, but the strong implication is that he feels his group are better suited to icing a winner than the current community-ownership: “I, and the people involved alongside me, have the best interests of the Lethbridge Hurricanes at heart and want to make the organization a successful WHL hockey club.”
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versteeg concedes that “ultimately, the future of this team is up to the shareholders,” and indeed, the board’s insistence over the summer that they were not interested in a sale indicates that having a willing seller may be the biggest obstacle to Versteeg and his group. However, if the board’s disinterest in listening to offers is not shared by a majority of shareholders, it could well become a contentious issue within the current ownership group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest advantage of maintaining a community-ownership model is the assurance that the team will not easily relocate, and with a smaller market like Lethbridge, that threat of relocation is always looming when financial losses mount. As far as private ownership goes, though, having Kris Versteeg leading the charge may be as safe from relocation as community-ownership. The former Hurricane who calls Lethbridge home has an interest in keeping the team here, and that may bode well for his chances of convincing shareholders to consider a sale. As he points out, Versteeg has remained an active participant in the local hockey community since becoming an NHLer, and that local-focus should be re-assuring to shareholders considering giving up their ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='the team is not for sale and the club has not be approached with any official offers'&gt;
While the letter has caused considerable buzz among fans this morning, Paul Kingsmith of Global Lethbridge &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paulkingsmith/status/393779503245189120&quot;&gt;points out an important point on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, noting that as of right now the team is not for sale and the club has not be approached with any official offers. He also points out that the WHL’s involvement in franchise sales means that if the Hurricanes were for sale, there is no assurance that Versteeg’s group would be the successful buyer, as we saw when some Saskatoon alumni were unsuccessful in buying the Blades this year. The WHL also has a less than stellar record when it comes to staying committed to local fanbases, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theprogress.com/sports/119043299.html&quot;&gt;as WHL fans in&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theprogress.com/sports/120330824.html&quot;&gt;Chilliwack will tell you&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, before you get too excited about the prospect of the Hurricanes entering a glorious new era under Versteeg’s direction, consider that the Hurricanes could just as easily end up sold to business interests in Vancouver, or sold to True North and relocated to Winnipeg. It’s a fun exercise to consider what could be, but don’t get your hopes up just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/versteeg-wants-to-own-the-hurricanes/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/versteeg-wants-to-own-the-hurricanes/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Give Thanks</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of Thanksgiving this week, I thought it appropriate to share some things that Hurricane fans have to be thankful for in the midst of the team&amp;#39;s slow start and current seven game losing streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. It’s always darkest before the dawn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four years without playoff hockey and a 1-9-0-1 start to this season. At some point the Hurricanes will start winning games with regularity, so we have that to look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. A brand of our own&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Capitals wordmark is gone from the Hurricanes’ sweaters which are also absent any Warner Brothers trademarked characters. Early reaction to the new logo was mixed, but even with my lukewarm feelings toward it, I am pleased that the team has its own visual identity that is suitable to represent the club for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. The goalie of the future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a team that has struggled for the past five years to develop a goaltending prospect in-house (Tai and/or Hogue may still prove me wrong), it is exciting to potentially see a starter on the horizon who won’t be 20 years old when he joins the Hurricanes. First round pick Stuart Skinner had a strong training camp and pre-season appearance and is off to a 3-0 start in the AMHL this season with a .920 save percentage. All the signs currently point to Skinner being the Hurricanes’ goalie of the future&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. Ryan Pilon’s birthday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, his late birthday that makes him ineligible for the 2014 NHL entry draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the NHL collective bargaining agreement defines player age:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As used in this Article, &amp;quot;age 18&amp;quot; means a Player reaching his eighteenth birthday between January 1 next preceding the Entry Draft and September 15 next following the Entry Draft, both dates included&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Pilon does not turn 18 until next October, he will be considered 17 for the purposes of the 2014 entry draft. That means Hurricane fans will potentially get to see him play one more season in the WHL than if he had been born a month earlier. Pilon should hear his name called early in the 2015 entry draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5. We don&amp;#39;t live in Medicine Hat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tigers may be a better team right now, but they&amp;#39;re in Medicine Hat, and that’s just not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/give-thanks/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/give-thanks/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>You Be The Video Goal Judge</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;During the second period of Thursday night’s game against he Calgary, the Hitmen scored a controversial goal that tied the game at 1-1. Pavel Padakin fired a shot from just in front of the goal line, sneaking it between Corbin Boes and the goalpost. It looked like a goal scorer’s goal until we got a second look at it, at which point it didn’t look like a goal at all. Let’s take a look at it, frame-by-frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first frame here you’ll see Boes’ crease area, but no puck yet. Padakin has just fired his shot from off screen, and the puck will later enter the frame from the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-0.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 0&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will now notice a dark streak come into the frame in front of Boes. That’s the puck coming toward the net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now lose sight of the puck for a few frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still no sign of the puck in the fifth frame, but something to take note of here is that Boes makes contact with the near post, jarring the net slightly. This will be more noticeable when you see it animated in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 4&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the sixth frame, the puck has re-appeared, making contact with the far goalpost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 5&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the next two frames, the puck is clearly moving away from the net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 6&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Frame 7&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here they are all strung together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-animated.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Animated&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my guess as to why the video review took so long, and why it was eventually ruled a goal. First, and imperatively here, the ruling on the ice was that this was a goal, so the video evidence had to conclusively show that a goal was not scored in order to overturn that call. There are two factors that I think can cause this to be inconclusive. The first being that we lose sight of the puck for a couple of frames worth of action. Best guess is that for at least one of those, the puck is obscured by the crossbar, but it’s hard to tell for sure, especially since this particular footage isn’t a high frame rate, so the fast moving puck turns into a blur pretty easily. We don’t really know where the puck is at all for a split second there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second factor that I think could cast some doubt here is the camera angle over the net. The goal line and the crossbar are both visible with the crossbar appearing immediately behind the goal line. In reality, the crossbar is directly above the goal line, so we have a bit of a parallax happening here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The illustration below demonstrates how the camera position above the net can make it appear as though a puck is directly beneath the crossbar, when in fact it has crossed the plane of the goal line. The red blocks at the top are the crossbar, the red blocks at the bottom are the goal line. The dotted line is the plane of the goal line that the puck must cross to score a goal, the the pink line is the area obscured from the overhead camera by the crossbar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.canescast.ca/web/goal-review-parallax.png&quot; alt=&quot;Parallax&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson here: If you can see the goal line and the crossbar at the same time and the puck is obscured by the crossbar, you can’t conclusively make a call based on that angle of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it gets right down to it, I still don‘t believe that the puck crossed the goal line. It’s hard to imagine a direct hit and roll off the post having actually crossed the line. That said, based on the video evidence that I have available, I don’t think I can make a case to conclusively overturn the call, either, so I may have to concede that the video goal judge made an appropriate call in allowing the goal to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/you-be-the-video-goal-judge/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/you-be-the-video-goal-judge/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>NHL is back</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The NHL gets back into action tonight, and it’s with a little extra interest that one Hurricane player will be watching the action. The Winnipeg Jets open their season against the Edmonton Oilers, only hours after &lt;a href=&quot;http://jets.nhl.com/club/news.htm?id=685083&quot;&gt;announcing they have signed Axel Blomqvist to a three year entry level contract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a good start to the week for Axel. He scored the winning goal in Sunday’s game against the Oil Kings while earning third star in the contest, and has now signed his first professional deal. Obviously, the Jets liked what they saw of Blomqvist during the Penticton prospects tournament, which featured a two-goal game, and their main camp, where he turned heads with his size and puck movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we know, Axel possesses the size and speed to be a successful power forward. In three games this season, he has tallied a goal and an assist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Everybody into the pool&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of the NHL season means it’s time to play in some hockey pools, and we’ve got just the one for you. Check out Dominion Lending Centre’s free hockey pool, and you could win as much as $100,000. Once you’re signed-up, make sure to join the CanesCast group and play against other Hurricane fans, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free pool. Cash prizes. What are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pool.dominionhockey.ca/dlc/hockey13/promo?agentID=10693&quot;&gt;Click here to join the pool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 21:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/nhl-is-back/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/10/nhl-is-back/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hecklers Row: The Lost Interview</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last season Mark sat down for a little chat with Hecklers Row. The audio of that interview got lost in the busyness of day-to-day life and was somehow never published. Until now. Today we are happy to finally release “Hecklers Row: The Lost Interview.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Hecklers Row in their natural habitat, comfortable in their seats at the Enmax Centre and just talking some hockey (and maybe even a bit of soccer). And yes, they even do some heckling. Thanks for recording with us, guys. Let’s do it again sometime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F113207672&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/09/heckers-row-lost-interview/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/09/heckers-row-lost-interview/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Canes earn three points with a flair of drama</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody can accuse this year’s Lethbridge Hurricanes of being boring. After a bumpy start to the year in last weekend’s home-and-home with the Tigers, the Hurricanes showed some third period spark in a pair of games this weekend, taking three of a possible four points on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being contained and outplayed for 40 minutes in Cranbrook on Friday night, the Hurricanes came to life in the third period, striking three times with the man advantage to force overtime before falling to the Ice in a shootout, 4-3. A similar storyline played out in Edmonton on Sunday afternoon when the Oil Kings took a 2-1 lead through two periods, outshooting the Hurricanes 37-13. A 42 second three goal outburst gave the ‘Canes all the offence they would need to get into the win column for the first time of the season. Russ Maxwell added an empty-netter in a 5-3 win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest in a line of twenty year old Hurricane goalies, Corbin Boes has so far looked every bit as good as Ty Rimmer before him through two games. While facing 89 shots, Boes has made 83 saves, posting a 2.88 goals against average and .933 save percentage. Those are encouraging numbers that indicate the veteran ‘keeper has not been set back by the off-season surgery that kept him out of training camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concern may be the early season shots on goal trend. Generally speaking, teams who register more shots on goal tend to score more goals. Teams who are outshot by an average of sixteen goals a game are probably going to find themselves on the losing end of things more often than not. That’s where the Hurricanes find themselves after two weekends, being outshot 164-99 so far, or a 41-25 per-game average. Exceptional goaltending can steal some wins, but even then Boes is going to need some more support than Hurricane goalies have been seeing so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head coach Drake Berehowski has repeatedly emphasized discipline as one of the characteristics that would identify his team. So far, though, his players have had a tough time staying out of the penalty box. The Hurricanes have found themselves shorthanded 22 times through the first four games, and have a middle-of-the-pack 77.3% success rate on the penalty kill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear there are some growing pains to overcome as this still young group adapts to the new coaching staff’s system. At the same time, a strong showing by a veteran netminder and the resiliency to fight back in the final twenty minutes in consecutive games are positive indicators of what is possible for the Hurricanes this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next action for the ‘Canes is Wednesday, October 2, a 7:00 start at the Enmax Centre against the Calgary Hitmen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://canescast.ca/article/2013/09/canes-earn-three-points-with-a-flair-of-drama/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://canescast.ca/article/2013/09/canes-earn-three-points-with-a-flair-of-drama/</guid>
        <author>
          <name>Josh Schroeder</name>
        </author>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>